Discover the past. Save the future.
Ghostbusters: Afterlife is a fantasy, comedy,
adventure film directed by Jason Reitman.
When single mom Callie and her two kids Trevor and Phoebe arrive in a small Oklahoma town, they begin to discover
their connection to the original Ghostbusters and the secret legacy their grandfather left behind.
Phoebe, played by Mckenna Grace.
Trevor, played by Finn Wolfhard.
Callie, played by Carrie Coon.
Sheriff Domingo, played by Bokeem Woodbine.
Grooberson, played by Paul Rudd.
Podcast, played by Logan Kim.
Ghostbusters: Afterlife is a 2021 American supernatural comedy film
directed by Jason Reitman, and written by Reitman and Gil Kenan.
It is the fourth in the Ghostbusters film series.
The film stars Carrie Coon, Finn Wolfhard, Mckenna Grace and Paul Rudd, with Annie
Potts and Ernie Hudson reprising their characters from the earlier films.
Set three decades after the events of Ghostbusters II, it follows a single mother and her children who move to an
Oklahoma farm they inherited from her estranged father Egon Spengler, a member of the original Ghostbusters.
A third Ghostbusters film had been in development since the release of Ghostbusters II,
but production stalled because Bill Murray refused to return to the series.
Following Harold Ramis' death on February 24, 2014, Sony Pictures
produced a female-led reboot, which was released in 2016.
In January 2019, it was announced that Jason Reitman would direct a sequel to the original films, with the new cast being announced by
July, while original cast members Potts, Hudson, Murray, Dan Aykroyd and Sigourney Weaver signed on two months later.
Principal photography took place from July to October of the same year.
After being delayed four times from an original July 2020 date due to the COVID-19 pandemic,
Ghostbusters: Afterlife was released in the United States on November 19 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
It grossed $204 million against a budget of $75 million.
A further sequel, Ghostbusters: Frozen Empire, was released in 2024.
The film explores themes of small town, afterlife,
ghostbuster, nostalgia, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.